<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Tianran Zhang</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intubation Prediction</title>
      <link>/project/intubationprediction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/intubationprediction/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ESP 2019 Data Analysis</title>
      <link>/project/capstone/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/capstone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Association of Numeracy Scales with Self-Reported Health Status and Healthcare-Provider Visits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Background&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Poor numeracy is likely to affect health because it may interfere with peoples’ ability to understand their health data and instructions from doctors.      &lt;strong&gt;Objective&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
To test the hypothesis that numeracy is associated with (a) self-reported health, and (b) healthcare-provider visits.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Study Design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Two survey studies, a random-digit-dial telephone survey in New York State (Empire State Poll), and an international survey on adult education (PIAAC).
&lt;strong&gt;Study Subjects&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
800 NYS residents aged over 18 in ESP and 3660 US residents aged over 16 in PIAAC.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Study Variables&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
ESP Predictor: numeracy measured by a 3-item version of the Subjective Numeracy Scale (SNS); Outcomes: self-report health status and healthcare-provider visits in the past 12 months. PIAAC Predictor: numeracy proficiency scale including 56 tasks. For both surveys, demographic covariates include gender, age, education, income, race, and ethnicity.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Results&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
(a) Weighted multivariate logistic regression on the dichotomized binary health status showed that people with higher numeracy scores tended to be in better health controlling other covariates. Education and income were positively associated with health status, while age was negatively associated with it. The results were similar to those of the nationwide PIAAC data, except that ethnicity was not associated with health status in PIAAC study. The ESP regression overperformed PIAAC regression with a lower AUC.&lt;br /&gt;
(b) Though the relationship between numeracy and visits to care providers were not significantly correlated, males and females showed different habits of visiting doctors. There was no association between numeracy and healthcare-provider visits in the female subset of ESP data controlling other covariates. However, the weighted ordinal multinomial regression showed that numeracy was negatively associated with doctor visits for males.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Higher numeracy is related to better self-reported health status. There is a gender difference in healthcare-providers visits that numeracy plays a role in males but not in the female subgroup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Faculty Advisor&lt;/em&gt;: Dr. Jessica Ancker&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Client&lt;/em&gt;: Dr. Jessica Ancker&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Team Members&lt;/em&gt;: Tianran Zhang, Haojia Li, Zihan Yang&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whole poster can be found &lt;a href=&#34;Capstone_Poster.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The draft of our data anlysis process can be downloaded &lt;a href=&#34;ESP_Draft.docx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heart Disease Prediction with ML methods</title>
      <link>/project/poster/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/poster/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The World Health Organization has estimated that 12 million deaths occur worldwide every year due to the heart disease. In the United States, cardiovascular diseases are the number 1 cause of death in adults. Early diagnosis is the key to prevent heart related deaths. Potential cardiovascular patients are often sent for multiple tests, and these test results help the doctors to make a diagnosis. The accuracy of the diagnosis often relies on the individual doctor’s knowledge and experiences. In order to improve the accuracy of the diagnosis, a group of medical researchers collected patient data from 4 national hospitals; two in the United States, and two in Europe. The data set HD.xlsx includes the patients age, gender, 11 test results, and ﬁnal diagnosis. The patient data from the two US hospitals and two European hospitals are saved in the 4 tabs, labeled “US1”, “US2”, “EU1”, “EU2”, respectively. The dictionary of all variables is saved in the tab “Dictionary”. Assume that no patient within is correlated with other patients within hospital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to ﬁnd the factors that signiﬁcantly contribute to the accuracy of diagnosis, I conducted two approaches sequentially.&lt;br /&gt;
a) Detect the presence of CVD: dichotomize the severity variable and consider the presence of narrowing vessel as response variable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;b) Predict the severity of CVD: build a model with the severity of heart disease as response variable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I developed several statistical models including GLM, KNN, SVM, and SDA to use the medical test results to help predict the likelihood of the presence of heart disease as well as its severity. The overall prediction accuracy is 84.78% in detecting the presence of CVD, and 64.1% in detecting the severity of CVD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also took a consideration on the costs of different test, and revise the final model with 6 predictors to balance between cost and effectivceness. The prediction accuracy for the revided model is 80.43% in predicting the presence of CVD, and 53.3% in predicting the severity of CVD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Test&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Cost&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;cp&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Immediate results, no additional cost&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;thestbps&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Immediate results, no additional cost&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;chol&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$7.27, need one day laboratory work&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;fbs&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$5.20, need one day laboratory work&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;restecg&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$15.50, need one day laboratory work&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;thalach&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$102.90, need one day laboratory work&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;exang&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$87.30, need one day laboratory work&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;oldpeak&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$87.30, need one day laboratory work&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;slope&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$87.30, need one day laboratory work&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ca&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$100.90, need one day laboratory work&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;thal&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$102.90, need one day laboratory work&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whole poster can be found &lt;a href=&#34;Poster_Tianran.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The full data set could be found and downloaded &lt;a href=&#34;HD.xlsx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The data anlysis process including all the corresponding codes, tables, and images can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://pedantic-hoover-44e272.netlify.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SCR Package</title>
      <link>/project/scr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/scr/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breast Cancer Analysis</title>
      <link>/project/breastcanceranalysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/breastcanceranalysis/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shiny App</title>
      <link>/project/shanyapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/shanyapp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Me and my group designed a shiny app (I was mainly in charge of coding part in ui and server) for Happy Valley Meat Company to calculate and visualize the invironmental impact for each cut of meat as the midterm project in Data Science class. The shinyio website can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://tianran.shinyapps.io/midterm_project/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FFD</title>
      <link>/project/ffd/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/ffd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Apply the algorithm about 3D Free Form Deformation (FFD) with the toolkit VTK. Plus, utilizing the 3D Face Resruction model PRNet, we realize the workflow of 2D-Face -&amp;gt; 3D-Face -&amp;gt; 3D-FFD. It&amp;rsquo;s a course project about visualization, working with Jing Wang and Donghao Li. The report can be found &lt;a href=&#34;pj_report.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;(In Chinese)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
